Curriculum Vitae

Roger Birkin

D.O.B - 03/07/1989

21 Poplar Road Bedminster Down Bristol BS13 7BP Home Telephone Number – (+44) 117 9394101 Mobile Number – (+44) 7983411500 Email – <u>rogbirkin@hotmail.co.uk</u>

Multi-skilled test engineer, with ten years' experience manufacturing and testing controls equipment for subsea oil and gas systems. Previously completed a four-year advanced modern apprenticeship with Vetco Gray Controls Ltd (currently Baker Hughes, a GE Oil and Gas Company). Extensive experience as a wiring technician, including building, wiring and modifying circuit boards, electrical systems, panels and cabinets from schematic drawings to IPC-A-610D and IPC/WHMA-A-620A standards. Practised at carrying out factory acceptance testing on topside controls equipment and fault-finding complex electrical systems down to component level. Adept at building, flushing and proof pressure testing (up to 1172 bar) subsea mechanical assemblies.

Qualifications

- HNC Level 4 Mechanical Engineering
- BOSIET, HUET & MIST Offshore Training
- Completed a four-year Advanced Modern Apprenticeship in Engineering
- NVQ Level 3 Mechanical Manufacturing Engineering (Fitting and Assembly)
- Edexcel Level 3 BTEC National Certificate Operations and Maintenance Engineering
- NVQ level 2 Performing Engineering Operations
- Key Skills Level 2 Application of Number, Communication, Information and Communication Technology

Career History

2014 to present - GE Oil and Gas Controls Ltd. (UK)

Position held – Mechanical Test Engineer

- Building hydraulic systems to engineering drawings.
- Flushing hydraulic systems to cleanliness standard SAE AS4059 and NAS 1638.
- Proof pressure testing hydraulic systems to pressures of 1172 Bar.
- Factory acceptance testing on topside/subsea oil and gas control systems.
- Offshore work, modifying and testing topside controls installations in Nigeria, America and United Kingdom.

2012 to 2014 - GE Oil and Gas Controls Ltd. (UK)

Position held - Electrical Test Engineer

- Board, Panel and cabinet wiring, inspection, testing and fault finding.
- Factory acceptance testing of Electrical Powered Coupling Modules, Surface Modem Units and Master Controls Systems.

- Installing Software using Windows and html Board Support Packages.
- Fault finding complicated electrical systems down to component level.
- Creating non-conformance reports and repair faults where necessary.
- IP networking and fault finding, DHCP, TCP and IPv4.
- Site receipt testing on customer-owned test equipment, including repair requirements and recommendations.

2010 to 2011 - Container Works (New Zealand)

- Loading, unloading and storing products from shipping containers.
- Handling dangerous chemicals.
- Working around heavy machinery.

2009 to 2010 - GE Oil and Gas Controls Ltd.

Position held – Electrical Wiring Technician

- Wiring and Soldering electrical units to IPC 610/620
- Reading and understanding electrical schematic drawings to build complicated electrical systems
- Producing sub-assemblies, Electrical Powered Coupling Modules, Surface Modem Units, Electrical Test Units and Master Control Stations
- Creating non-conformance reports and repair faults

2005 to 2009 - Vetco Gray Control Ltd. (Currently GE Oil and Gas)

Position held - Apprentice (4 Year Multi-skilled advanced modern apprenticeship)

- Wiring and fitting components to circuit boards
- Building, wiring and modifying panels and cabinets
- Building and testing Subsea Control Modules
- Flushing hydraulic systems using HPU's to cleanliness standards SAE AS4059 and NAS 1638
- Pre-charging accumulators
- Factory acceptance testing subsea systems

References - References can be provided on request